TINA ZHAO

github.com/manacake • Redwood City, CA • tinayzhao@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Tina is a dedicated full-stack engineer with excellent troubleshooting skills, creative spunk, and a passion for problem solving. Her background includes a strong knowledge of Javascript and Python. She is familiar with the fast-paced dynamic of startups and has extensive experience with mobile/web application development. She is also a well-organized multitasker with superb interpersonal skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, Python, Ruby, Agda, Scala, C++

Node.js / Express / Django

Angular.js / Handlebars / EJS

HTML5 / CSS3 / Sass / Bootstrap

Git / Subversion

Heroku / Parse

Other: ¡Query, Keen / Mixpanel, PostgreSQL, Unity, Linux, Illustrator / Photoshop

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Developer (Sep 2014 – Present) Prompt.ly, San Francisco, CA

Designed and engineered the application UI (mobile and web) using wireframes and programmed the user workflow throughout the stack

Architected and implemented key features of the application including payments, subscriptions, locations, etc. while integrating with vendor APIs

Refactored the application's entire CSS structure, replacing it with Sass

Fixed bugs quickly by utilizing an agile software development process

Engineered the code used to supply the business with critical analytics and marketing data

Built and refactored various spiders to scrape data from qualified leads in an effort to grow customer base

Worked directly with executive and engineering leadership to analyze and plan sprints

Trained new team members on stack technologies as part of the onboarding process

Participated in regular sessions with focus groups and application users in an effort to improve the product and deliver excellence

Front End Web Developer (Aug 2008 – Sep 2014) West Wind Education Policy, Inc., Iowa City, IA

Designed visuals for use by in-house and state-level clientele

Turned client deliverables into interactive web tools

Provided upkeep on all company websites and databases

Initiated and maintained social networking sites for client projects

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Pictograph Box (Python)

Implemented a database-backed blog engine with Django; Current version deployed on Heroku

Blog engine included categories/tags, comments, pagination, rss, search, and sitemaps

Used a test driven development approach for each new feature added

Utilized linting to analyze code for potential errors and completeness

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science, May 2014 University of Iowa - Iowa City, IA

University of California Davis - Davis, CA (Aug 2005 – Jun 2007) Studied Japanese language, history, and culture